if you're on the internet at all and you
knit or crochet I guarantee you've heard
of the Sophie scarf by petite knit this
is one of the most viral knitting
patterns it's definitely having a moment
right now I think Min scarves in general
are having a moment right now and like
triangle scarves but I wanted to create
a version for people that just crochet
because I haven't seen like a comparable
dupe for it I tried a few different
versions and I ended up really liking
the way that this slip stitch was
looking I think it mimics the Garter
Stitch nicely and once it's blocked it
has a really nice drape like you can
tell this just flops around and it's not
stiff at all for both of these I used
around 50 g of a DK weight yarn for this
blue one I used Pearl Soho's knitting
yarn which is ironic because I'm not
knitting with it but it's 100% Marino
wool and this one is a little scratchier
not scratchy a little more like robust
feeling than this one but it's still
really soft and I am so so sensitive
when it comes to like fabrics and itch
Factor so I definitely can tolerate this
one so if you're looking for something
this is only around $12 a skin I think
it's pretty cheap and this one was made
with Rowan's pure alpaca yarn I believe
this is the color oat and this is the
color Hydro Blue if you want the same
color but this one is definitely a lot
softer it has more of like a Halo or
fuzz to it and it feels really cozy on
your neck I just wanted to say say if
you are opting for a natural fiber yarn
I would use either a really soft cotton
or linen yarn if you don't care about it
being warm or Marino wool is soft alpaca
is soft just keep that in mind when
you're picking yarn for this because if
it's itchy you're never going to wear it
I also know that there are some really
soft acrylic or like synthetic Yarns out
there so do whatever you want just make
sure it's soft and I highly highly
highly recommend blocking this I show
you how to do it at the end once I
finish the scarf if you've never done it
before but it totally transforms the
shape of it and the drape of it and the
softness blocking with this pattern is
definitely non-negotiable I really love
the versatility of this scarf since I've
had this one and then I have a red one
that is made with single crochet it's a
little bit uglier um but I've been
wearing them more than I thought because
you can wear them so many different ways
I've seen people tie it and wear it like
this with a jacket or something I've
seen people do like a little scarf like
that I feel like commonly the way that
petite knit like shows it is with it
centered in the front and then you pull
it around and then tie it off to the
side it feels so French to me or like a
flight attendant but I think it's so
cute I also have worn it with my hair
down as a headband like just to keep
myself warm on a walk and you could just
tie it back there I even feel like you
could do like off the
shoulder just toss back and then like
put your coat on and it kind of feels
like a turtleneck or something but
overall it's super versatile it took
like half of a day to finish so it's a
really quick project for crochet I
definitely think if you're a beginner
you could do this as long as you are
able to count and keep track of Rose
before we get into the video I want to
take a second to talk about ritual who
is sponsoring this portion of the video
I'm someone who pays attention to
ingredients and tries to make sure that
what I put in my box body is as clean as
possible which is why I love ritual all
of their products are made traceable
which means that they tell you where
their ingredients come from why they're
there and how their products are
validated I've been loving rituals
essential protein 18 plus which is a
clean plant-based formula that contains
a complete amino acid profile and has 20
g of protein I feel like I'm always on
the hunt for a protein powder that's
really clean but also tastes good and
this protein powder definitely checks
all of my boxes I take this in the
morning before I work out just to have
something in my stomach I just do one
scoop dissolved in water and it's super
smooth it's not chalky and it has a
really nice vanilla flavor that's not
too sweet it's soyf free glutenfree
vegan friendly and contains no GMOs
Stevia sugar or artificial colors
flavors or sweeteners it's made with a
pea protein derived from regeneratively
farmed peas grown in the USA and it only
has 10 simple ingredients I've also been
using ritual stress relief which has a
trio of clinically studied ingredients
that help the body with stress Stress
Management it has ashwagandha alanine
and saffron that support fast acting and
sustained stress relief and it really
helps me feel a lot calmer and more
relaxed throughout the day I also take
it in the morning because it releases
over the course of 8 hours so I really
notice a difference when I take it
versus mornings that I don't I highly
recommend trying out ritual if you've
been looking for a high quality
supplement brand you can use my code
aluts 25 or the link in my description
to get 25% off your first order thank
you again to Ritual for sponsoring this
portion of the video so I'm using a DK
or light worsted way yarn the one I'm
going to be using to demonstrate this
with is Rowan's pure alpaca yarn in the
color oat I'm also using a 4 and 1/2 mm
hook and then you're also going to need
some kind of yarn needle I'm also going
to block the scarf at the end which I'll
show you but um this isn't necessary but
I am going to use this wool wash it just
is a really light gentle detergent that
is going to help soften up the fibers
when I get wet oh and a measuring tape
also will be helpful because there's not
going to be a gauge swatch for this
we're just kind of building it to
measurements okay I'm starting by making
a slip knot and inserting my
hook as we start out we're going to
start with a very small number of
stitches so it might get kind of hard to
see I apologize I'm going to do my best
to show you what's going on but uh let
me talk through the pattern really
quickly so we're going to start with two
two stitches and every five rows I'm
going to increase one so in the
beginning we're going to do five rows of
two
stitches then we're going to increase
one so we will have three stitches and
do five total rows with three stitches
increase one five total rows with four
stitches increase one five total rows
with five stitches and so on and every
five rows we'll keep increasing by one
and eventually we'll get to our desired
width which you'll see in a minute but I
just wanted to set that structure up for
you so it makes sense what we're doing
I'm going to start by chaining three
one 2 3 now we're going to be doing slip
stitches but every row we will be
chaining one as our turning chain
otherwise things just get a little bit
too tight so these first two chains are
our first two stitches and this is our
turning chain which we're ignoring and
not working in now I'm going to work my
slip stitches for Row one and I prefer
to work in do the back bumps of the
chain but you can do whatever you prefer
so skipping the first chain from my hook
I'm just inserting my hook into the back
bump yarning over pulling up a
loop and then pulling that Loop through
the loop that was already on my hook and
you want to make sure that your tension
is not too tight or it becomes really
really hard to work um these uh slip
stitches again in the last or second
Stitch of this row
I insert my
hook yarn over pull up a loop again if
this is too tight you're going to have a
hard time give it a little bit of
slack and then pull that through the
loop on my hook that is our first row
and it might not look like much but
we're getting somewhere then I'm going
to chain and
turn from here on out we're doing slip
stitches in the front loops and I'll
show you what that looks like if you've
never done that before so again this
right here is the Turning chain ignoring
that we have two v's here for two
stitches and this is the back Loop this
back part of the V because it's furthest
away from me and the leg of the V that's
closest to you is called the front Loop
which you can see here in this
Stitch and here in this Stitch so we're
only working in the front part of those
stitches so I'm continuing on my second
row working in the front Loop of those
stitches you kind of have to use your
nail because there's no like fabric to
hold on to yet since there's so few
stitches that it gets a little bit
tricky but as long as you look for that
V you can get your hook in
there and that is our second
row repeating chaining one and turning
on our third row we're doing the exact
same thing front Loop
slip
stitches chaining one and turning this
is my fourth
row working front Loop slip
stitches and one more time chaining
turning and working our fifth row
chaining and turning okay there was no
increases done here because we started
with two as our foundation chain but as
I said from here on out we're going to
be increasing so I did five I start from
scratch now this is going to be Row one
and it's going to have three stitches so
we need to increase one time if you look
at the top this is the chain so I'm
covering that up we have two stitches
when there's more stitches I usually
will look for the center Stitch as the
place that I'm going to increase but
right now obviously there's no Center
Stitch the center is technically in
between these two stitches so I'm just
going to work my increase in the first
Stitch it doesn't really matter here but
just note that some rows if they're even
won't have a center Stitch so you can
work in the Stitch before Center if that
makes sense otherwise just follow what
I'm doing
but into that front Loop for our slip
stitch increases we're going to work two
slip stitches into that same front Loop
space so this is just like normal I did
a front Loop slip stitch then I'm going
to look where the yarn's coming from and
into that exact same Loop not the next
Stitch that same loop I stick my hook
and I do another slip stitch again
making sure it's not too tight
and then here you can see I have one
stitch left of this row so I'm going to
finish that for a total of three
stitches so that counted as our Row one
for the threes so now I need to do four
more rows of Threes without
increasing that was row two chain and
turn this is Row
three chain and
[Music]
turn row
four chain and turn and one more for row
five chain and turn since we did five
rows of two and five rows of three now
we need to do five rows of four so I'm
starting over for Row one this is going
to be my increase row now with these
three stitches I do have a center Stitch
so I'm going to work my increases into
this middle Stitch here I'm doing one
normal slip
stitch two slip stitches into that
Center Front
Loop
one
two and one into that last Stitch so now
I have four and I'm going to continue
four rows of normal non- increase rows
for a total of five rows
I finished my fifth row of four stitches
I'm chaining one turning my work
starting back at Row one which is my
increase row
again I have four stitches which means
there's no Center so I'm going to
increase if this is Stitch 1 2 3 4 on
Stitch two which is to the right of the
center
I just finished my fifth row of five as
we keep going with our increases it's
going to keep getting wider and wider
I'm going to continue this same pattern
of sets of five rows where I'm
increasing on the first row by one
stitch and I will come back and tell you
how many total rows I did I just
finished my fifth row of 18 stitches so
I completed since we didn't start at one
we started at two 17 sets of that five
row increase if that's confusing to you
just stop once you've done your fifth
row of 18 stitches you also could alter
this number I got this height from kind
of the height that I want it to be on my
neck if you have a super long neck you
could add more stitches but just note
that that's going to make your scarf a
little bit longer so you might want to
cut out some of the center rows also
something to note with this Stitch is
because we did front Loop slip stitches
it is really stretchy so when we block
it it's going to gain a lot of length so
just keep that in mind currently it is
12 in or 30 cm but again once I blocked
it my measurement increas quite a bit so
just use that as a reference but don't
freak out if yours is a little bit
longer or shorter now that we've done
our increases we are now going to work a
large portion of the scarf with no
increases um as our middle section so
I'm just going to continue front Loop
slip stitches for a while until I'm
ready to do the same thing on the other
side but reversed but for now I will put
on the screen how many inches I did of
non- increased rows and I will meet you
back once I finish I just worked my
midsection without any decreases it is
about 21 or 22 cm so we are essentially
doing the same thing as the increase row
just reversed instead of increasing as
our first row and then doing four
regular rows increasing four regular
we're going to do the opposite so we're
actually going to work four rows without
decreasing and then our fifth row will
will be our decrease row and then we'll
continue that four more rows without
decreasing decrease row I'm going to
work four rows and then come back to
show you how to decrease on my fifth row
I got four rows in to my decrease
section and I have worked up to the
middle of my row so for decreasing it's
kind of the opposite of the other side
where we either worked two stitches into
the middle Stitch or the Stitch right
before the middle for decreasing we're
either going to work work the two
stitches on either side of the middle so
that they become one stitch or the
middle Stitch and the one before it as
you'll work them you'll see what I mean
but these are the two middle stitches
for this row because we have an even
number so there is a center split and
I'm going to be working both of them for
my decrease so there's two ways to
decrease with a slip stitch this is my
preferred method but if you have another
way you prefer go for it um I'm still
working in the front Loops as I normally
would but I'm going to grab both of
these stitched Loops before I pull some
yarn through so what that looks like is
I grab my front Loop of that first
Stitch and normally we would pull
through right but I'm not going to do
that I'm going to also insert it in the
next
Stitch so I have both of those two
stitches Loops front loops on my hook
and I'm going to yarn over and just pull
through everything on my hook look and
that is my decrease then I'm going to
continue down the row as I normally
would just with front
loops and that is what your decrease row
will look like it's pretty invisible but
I'm going to repeat this again now that
I have one less Stitch so I should have
17 let's check yeah I have 17 stitches
so I'm going to continue with that
pattern of four rows without decreasing
one row decreasing four rows decrease
four rows decrease four rows DEC
increase you want to continue this
pattern of decreasing every five rows
until you have two stitches so that we
mimic what happened with our increase
rows once you decrease to two stitches
you just want to make sure that you have
five total rows at the end with two
stitches and I will meet you back I've
gotten to five rows of two which marks
the end of my scarf so my total scarf
measures around 90 CM now I'm going to
show you how to do the Border I still
have a decent amount of yarn left that I
should be able to finish my border with
and not start a new ske which is great
for the Border it's essentially just a
fancy single crochet so to reference the
one that I already have finished it does
give it a little more roundness than
just a plain single crochet which I feel
like looks pretty finished and Polished
and I like it a lot so going to show you
how to do it so here you can see I did
my last last slip stitch and since I
ended off on the left here I'm going to
keep my yarn attached and work along my
scarf this way and I want to show you
the holes that I'm going to be working
into it doesn't necessarily matter which
space you're working into it's just that
you're consistent when I pull
apart the scarf there are naturally
these little holes here
whoops there are naturally these holes
these are the spaces I'm going to be
working through I'm going to skip this
first one because that's right where my
yarn is attached and I'm going to work
into this next hole I'm going to zoom
out a little bit cuz we're going to get
crazy
with the hook
but I start by inserting my hook because
we're just doing single crochet normally
you would pull up a loop and pull
through I am going to pull up a loop so
I inserted my
hook and pulled up a loop and instead of
yarning over I'm actually going to take
my hook and kind of hold it like this
and I'm going to wrap my yarn behind and
to the right and in front of my
hook and what that's going to do is like
cinch these two pieces
together and you want to make sure that
right here it's not pulled too tight but
it's also not too loose where you're
going to finish the Stitch and there's
no tension here you want there to be
enough tension that it feels kind of
like a normal single crochet would I
guess is the best way to explain it like
I still have some tension with my left
hand then you're going to yarn over and
pull through
two I'll do it again in the next hole if
you just kind of pull the workart
naturally it would be right here insert
your hook pull up a
loop you can kind of get the hang of
this like I eventually would just kind
of like quickly do this motion as I went
through but again you're pulling it
behind to the right and in front of your
work making sure that from the last
Stitch there's enough tension there and
then yarning over and pulling through
two I'll keep doing it to show
you I bring the yarn
behind and in front of my hook and then
pull the tension to the left bring it
behind my hook so that I can yarn
over and then pull
through and just do that around the
entire scarf it does take some time to
get used to especially like readjusting
your tension after you come around but
obviously you have to do it a million
times and the more you do it you'll get
better at it and faster with it biggest
thing to avoid again is like if there
isn't enough tension or if it gets
caught like for example here if I were
to yarn over and pull through this Loop
is going to be super loose so again make
making sure right there it pulls just
enough that there's not a gaping Loop
you'll see that the Edge gets this
really nice finished look and adds a
little more height and yeah again like
roundness to it so that it separates it
and gives the look of an eye cord or at
least as close as we can get with
crochet I'm just going to show you
quickly cuz I am going to come back one
day work all the way around but once you
get to the other smaller Edge you still
want to work in this Stitch this Stitch
and then I do want you to work where
your yarn was attached here so once kind
of on the end and then similarly to how
we started before the next hole if you
think of it this way there's kind of
like one two three we'll have a stitch
here A Stitch here and then a stitch
here so there shouldn't be two stitches
worked on this Edge just where the holes
are so hole hole hole and then continue
I didn't slip stitch to my first Stitch
yet of the Border I just finished on
this edge here but I wanted to show you
how to connect back to the first
stitches that we did so if you remember
when we started there was the two end
stitches and then we started our border
so if you look here you can actually see
those two stitches so there is a stitch
here A Stitch here and then you see like
that twist Stitch from the border if I
just stop at the last hole where my
chain was I would have to connect it
like that and then this would be
sticking out just find a space on that
end and you're going to work one
more of those border
stitches so that you have kind of a
bridge between the two sides and now I'm
a little bit closer so I'm going to find
the Twist here like that little Loop
that sticks out and right before it
there are two strands here I'm going to
slip stitch into these um stitches so
I'm going to find
them and do a slip
stitch and you can kind of tighten that
and you'll see that that end ends up
laying pretty flat instead of
puckering and to finish off I just chain
one extra I leave a decent Siz tail and
cut my yarn and then pull the yarn all
the way through to make a little
knot and you are done it's okay if this
Edge has a little pucker to it it's
natural that the width of these stitches
is not going to be exactly the height of
these rows if that makes sense so when
we block it it's going to relax I do not
recommend making this if you're not
going to block it it completely
transforms it weave your ends in and
grab a bowl of water and some wool wash
or detergent or hair conditioner or
something and I will meet you in a
minute to block blocking is really
simple so all you want to do is I'm
using this bowl because I feel weird
like using the raw sink but do whatever
you want and you want to fill it with
lukewarm
water you definitely don't want it to be
hot but I think that it softens it a
little bit more if it's kind of warm
this is the wool wash that I use but you
want to just add a tiny tiny bit because
we're not using a lot of water and we're
also blocking a really small item I just
make sure the soap is dissolved in there
and like all mixed up before I put the
scarf in and
then you just stonk it makes me think of
Nicki Minaj she's like looks like I'm
going for a swim that's how I feel
you'll already notice like as I lifted
it I can just like feel it expanding
which is good because we want it to be a
little longer a lot of times it will
like float to the surface which is
probably fine but I like to like weight
it down so I'll just take the
soap and like set it on top of it
probably doesn't even matter but it's
just something I always do leave it for
15 minutes and you're going to ring the
water out I'll meet you back in 15 it's
been about 10 minutes I'm impatient so
I'm just going to take it out now I have
some old hand towels here that I'm going
to use to get some of the water out but
you want to first try to squeeze out as
much as you can so again definitely do
not ring it or twist it or anything
crazy because it's going to damage the
fibers but I like to just roll it up and
then squeeze
it as much as I can just with my
hand I love blocking wool it smells
like like a farm it smells kind of Milky
it's like really subtle it's really nice
it reminds me of when used to give um we
used to have a multi poo little um puppy
and giving him a bath it would kind of
smell like this just be gentle get out
as much water as you can with your hand
and then in the towel stretch out the
scarf and just start
rolling so that it's fully rolled up
like a little burrito and then I'm
actually going to put it on the ground
and step on it right where the scarf is
and this is just pushing as much water
out as possible it'll dry a lot faster
then I take it over to my blocking mat
these are just old pieces from our gym
flooring um our basement is under
construction so there's like a ton of
dust I did wipe this down but in case it
looks dirty that's what that is I'm
going to stretch it out a lot because I
want it to be
longer you want to make sure it's even
make sure those edges are pulled flat
everything is straight I'm just going to
put a few pins to keep it in place in
case it gets kicked or something but
honestly you don't have to if you don't
feel like it you want it to be anywhere
from like 110 to 120 CM my blue one
after blocking I think was 118 cm and
this one is3 114 CM so make sure you are
stretching it fully to be that long if
you want it to be like mine I'm just
going to let this sit here overnight and
I will come back tomorrow and show you
the result I'm wearing my blue one now
but obviously since I filmed that I've
taken the cream one off of The Blocking
mat and just to show you like how nice
of a drape it has after blocking it got
a lot softer if you make this scarf I
love seeing what you guys make from my
videos you can either DM it to me on
Instagram or tag me in a post I feel
like I'm more likely to see stuff there
than on like Tik Tok or something but my
Instagram is @ alz nuts thanks again for
watching and I'll see you in my next
video
[Music]